在本讲座开始时，我们会考虑为什么如果我拿着一张纸的问题
At the beginning of this lecture, we consider the problem of why if I hold a sheet of paper
在场景前面，我在那张纸上看不到图像。原因
up in front of the scene, I do not see an image on that sheet of paper. And the reason
因为我们谈到的是，在论文的任何特定点，我们记录了
for that as we talked about was that at any particular point on the paper, we record the
落在那个特定点并且光线来自的总光量
total amount of light that's falling on that particular point and that light has come from
现实世界中非常非常多的要点。我们记录了那里的总光量。
very, very many points in the real world itself. We've recorded the total amount of light there.
我们没有谈到光线来自的方向。
We didn't say anything about the direction that the light rays came from.
那么，如果我们能够在每个点实际记录的不仅仅是光量，而且还有
So, what if we could actually record at each point not just the amount of light but the
光的来源方向？这让我们进入所谓的光之区
direction that the light came from? This gets us into the area of what's called a light
领域。现在，一个光场，在数学上，它是一个描述光的功能
field. Now, a light field is, mathematically, it's a function that describes the light that's
在空间的每一个点上向每一个方向行进。
travelling in every single direction at every single point in space.
想想你现在所处的房间。考虑其中的任何特定点
Think about the room that you're in at the moment. Consider any particular point in that
房间里会有大量的光线穿过那个点，他们会
room and there'll be a large number of light rays passing through that point and they will
来自房间内的许多其他点。
have come from many many other points within the room.
因此，非常非常复杂的光线，都会向不同的方向发展
So, very, very complex lots of light rays, all going different directions and coming
来自不同的地方。
from different places.
因此，光场传感器试图捕获其中的一些，以捕获颜色和强度
So, a light field sensor attempts to capture some of that, to capture the color, the intensity
和所有这些光线的矢量方向。传统相机简单地加起来
and the vector direction of all these rays of light. Traditional camera simply adds up
所有的光线并记录总和。光场相机尝试记录
all the rays of light and records the sum total. Light field cameras try to record the
方向也是方向非常重要。再考虑这个例子
directions as well and the direction is really important. Consider this example again of
薄透镜模型。我们在世界上有一个对象。这是一大堆光线
the thin lens model. We have an object in the world. It's a whole bunch of light rays
让物体通过镜头并穿过焦平面。
leaving the object passing through the lens and passing through the focal plane.
我在这里展示了一个像素，进入该像素的光线来自
I've shown here a pixel and the light rays that are entering that pixel are coming from
大量不同的方向。让我们动画这个，你可以看到那个对象
a large number of different directions. Let’s animate this, you can see that the object
正在移动，我们可以看到来自该物体尖端的光线穿过像素阵列。
is moving and we can see the light rays from the tip of that object moving across the array of pixels.
因此，当它真正接近镜头时，它将成为传统的焦点
So, the object when it's really close to the lens would be well out of focus in the traditional
相机。然而，正在发生的是那些光线现在正在一个范围内
camera. What's happening though is that those light rays are now following across a range
像素和每个像素，这些光线以不同的角度进入。
of pixels and that each pixel, those light rays are entering at a different angle.
因此，如果这些像素不仅能够记录光量而且能够记录方向
So, if those pixels were able to record not just the amount of light but the direction
他们来自哪里，甚至可以计算图像
at which they are coming from as well, it would be possible to compute the image even
虽然它非常非常失焦，但这是一种开始出现的技术
though it is very, very out of focus and this is a technology that's starting to emerge
现在在所谓的光场相机。
now in what's called light field cameras.
现在，市场上第一个，消费级别的光场相机，这一个产生
Now, one of the first on the market, the consumer level of light field cameras, this one produced
通过Lytro和本幻灯片的右侧，我们可以看到的是光场
by Lytro and in the right hand side of this slide, what we can see is the light field
正在对图像进行后处理以使图像的特定部分成为焦点。所以，这个人
image being post-processed to bring a particular part of the image into focus. So, the person
点击图像中的特定点并使用来自的所有原始信息
is clicking on a particular point in the image and using all the raw information from the
光场，光量及其方向，我们可以计算出适当的焦点图像。
light field, the amount of light and its direction, we can compute the appropriate in focus image.
我们不能让图像中的每个点始终聚焦，但我们现在可以选择
We cant let every point in the image in focus at all the time but we can now select after
我们拍摄了我们想要关注的部分，这是向前迈出的一大步。
we took the picture which part we would like to have in focus and that's a big step forward.
早期版本的光场相机，其研究版本非常非常
Early versions of light field cameras, the research versions of these were very very
大量的相机，非常昂贵，远非便携式。这是一个例子
massive arrays of cameras, very expensive and far from portable. Here's an example of
早期的便携式光场相机。再一次，一系列试图捕捉的相机
an early portable light field camera. Again, an array of cameras, which are trying to capture
来自世界的光线以及它们来自的各个方向。
the light rays coming from the world and the various directions at which they've come from.
这是一项现在的技术，随着手机的成本变得越来越容易获得
This is a technology now, which is becoming quite accessible as the cost of phones is
减少。现在可以创建大量的摄像机和这些视频
being reduced. It's now possible to create enormous arrays of cameras and these videos
展示一些使用商用手机相机，廉价数码相机完成的工作
show some work that's being done using commodity mobile phone cameras, cheap digital cameras
为了能够捕获光场，一旦你有一个捕获的光场，那么，
in order to be able to capture light fields and once you have a captured light field then,
你可以执行一些非常惊人的视觉效果，停止动作效果等。
you can perform some very amazing visual effects, stop motion effects and so on.